ROBINSON ONOKUREFE AGAGA

WEB DEVELOPER

Address: No.54, Siga House, Behind St Joseph Catholic Church,

Winners Street, Agudama, Bayelsa State, Nigeria.

Phone: (+234) 08032454342.

E-mail: robinsonagaga@gmail.com.

Facebook: https://web.facebook.com/robinson.agaga

Twitter: https://twitter.com/RobinsonAgaga

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/agaga-robinson-837587198/.

OBJECTIVE

Have over 13 years working experience in Software Development as a computer programmer. Have expertise and experience in all phases of software development life cycle namely; analysis, design and coding, testing and implementation. Have experience in working with different Programming Languages, operating systems and platforms. Robinson Agaga has developed several web and desktop applications and also has experience in Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and Public Relations (PR) campaigns through verticals such as blogs, YouTube, Facebook, Twitter and Instagram. In addition, Robinson Agaga is also a talented graphics designer. He has undergone several certified trainings in the field of Software Development, Graphics Designing and Geographic Information System (GIS).

PERSONAL INFORMATION

State of Origin: Bayelsa State.

Local Government Area: Sagbama.

Date of Birth: 25th -Oct-1985.

Sex: Male.

Marital Status: Married.

EDUCATION

- National Youth Service Corp Certicate, 2011.
- B.SC, Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology, 2010.
- Diploma, Web Development, 2008.

Local Government Primary School Majidun, 1998.

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Proficient in the following Computer Programming Languages: Python, Java, PHP, Laravel (PHP Framework), JavaScript, HTML, CSS. Including Eclipse and Android studio
- Proficient in map creation software (ESRI ARCGIS Desktop and Online).
- Proficient in SQL Database Development.
- Proficient in Graphics Design using Fireworks, Photoshop and Coreldraw.

STRENGTHS:

- Efficient Computer Programming Skill.
- Excellent Communication Skill.
- Excellent Analytical Skill.
- Efficient Graphics Designing skill

WORK EXPERIENCE

I. Web Analyst (August 2017 – September 2019).

Social Media Aide to Hon. Commissioner for Information and Orientation Bayelsa State, Daniel Iworiso-Markson.

Responsibilities: Was among the team behind the Social handle of Bayelsa State Ministry of Information and Orientation on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram. I write Contents, Design graphics and also do research. Aside the routine of developing contents and writing events report, as a programmer, I designed an online system we use to track the number of click a link shared on Facebook or twitter get. I also came up with a strategy we use to spread any content across the country in few minutes. I was in the Situation Room during the 2019 House of Reps and Assembly elections. I designed a system that centralized all the reports received from correspondents in the various Local Government Areas in Bayelsa State for easy visual presentation.

II. Senior Programmer (August 2015 – February 2017).

Synchron Platforms International, Bayelsa State, Nigeria.

Development Environment: PHP (Code Igniter and Laravel frame work), Java and Python.

Responsibilities: handling of software development projects. Handled several projects including web and desktop applications. The software I developed include an automobile simulation system, Information Management Systems and several websites and blogs.

III. Webmaster (April 2014 – July 2015)

Kaiste Ventures, Publishers of Nigerian Seminars and Trainings.com. Lagos, Nigeria.

Development Environment: PHP (from scratch coding and Framework), Java.

Responsibilities: I worked as an in-house web developer. As a webmaster, was responsible for developing and implementing new functionalities in the website, provision of technical support (trouble shooting and debugging), Application optimization(W3C, Attracta, Google developer tools) and backend interphase programming.

https://www.nigerianseminarsandtrainings.com/

IV. Web Programmer (Apr 2013 – Mar 2014)

Cedar Field Designs, Lagos, Nigeria.

Development Environment: PHP, Laravel (PHP Framework).

Responsibilities: As a web programmer I handled the task of developing codes in PHP. I was assigned to numerous web application development projects which I delivered within the required time. I worked with a team of 2 programmers and was also involve in graphics and logo designing for corporate branding. https://www.cedarfielddesign.com/

VERIFIED CERTIFICATION

- Geographic Information System (GIS), a 3 Course Specialization by University of Toronto on Cousera November 2019.
- Python Programming for Everybody, A 5 course specialization by University of Michigan on Cousera November 2019.
- Database Management by SATNET Computer Institute, 2011.

REFFREES

Available on request.